Russell E. Harmon

Contact Information Rochester Institute of Technology 39 Nathaniel Rochester Hall Rochester, NY 14623 (863) 514-7014

2710 Avenue J NW Winter Haven, FL 33881 russ@eatnumber1.com blog.eatnumber1.com

OBJECTIVE

I am looking for a three to six month co-op starting June.

SUMMARY

I am a person who loves to tinker. I spend the majority of my free time working on personal projects. Some of the projects I have worked on include the Linux kernel and the Gentoo Linux distribution. As a result, I've found that I have become very good at picking up new ideas quickly, and expanding what I already know with little more than the internet and a direction.

EDUCATION

Rochester Institute of Technology - Rochester, NY

September 2006 - Present

• Major: B.S./M.S. Computer Science

• M.S. GPA: 3.0 • Minor: Music

• Expected graduation: June 2012

EXPERIENCE

Gentoo Linux - Gentoo Foundation

Package Maintainer

August 2007 - Present http://www.gentoo.org/

Sole maintainer of the PCSX2 ebuilds. An ebuild is a bash script which fetches, unpacks, compiles and installs a piece of software. PCSX2 is a Play Station 2 emulator.

SafeNet Inc - Belcamp, MD

Engineering Intern

June 2008 - Present

http://www.safenet-inc.com/

Worked on the SafeNet Management Console (SMC) on a team of 7. SMC is a web application built on Java, JBoss, Hibernate and JSF which manages high speed network encryption devices that SafeNet manufactures, including top-secret devices. Responsibilities included (a) creating requirements documents, (b) implementing requirements (IPv6, file synchronization), (c) testing and (d) fixing defects. Some of the specific tasks that were assigned while working there included transparent file synchronization between machines, implementing IPv6 support and implementing support for multiple SMC servers managing the same device (distributed devices).

New York City Department of Education - Bronx, NY IT Specialist

September 2002 - June 2006http://schools.nyc.gov/

Worked at Lehman High School. The work there included (a) setup and maintain the computer systems, (b) repair and maintain the network, (c) diagnose and eliminate viruses and malware on the school's network and computer systems and (d) audit the network for malicious activity.

CERTIFICATIONS

TECHNICAL SKILLS & Languages (a) Java (b) C/C++ (c) BASH & other SH derived scripting languages (d) Python Operating Systems (a) Linux - Gentoo, Debian, OpenWRT (e) Solaris (f) Windows (g) OSX

> Hardware (a) Server Maintenance (b) Networking (c) Network Security Tools (a) LATEX(b) Microsoft Office (c) Vim (d) Idea (e) Regex (f) Autotools

Certifications (a) Cisco Academy, with honors (terms 1 and 2) (b) A+ (c) MOUS (Word)

EXTRACURRICULAR

US FIRST Robotics Team 1230 - Lead programmer http://www.usfirst.org/ CSH (Computer Science House) - Network Administrator http://www.csh.rit.edu/ Rocking the Boat - Built a boat for children from the South Bronx http://www.rockingtheboat.org/

Honors & Awards

NYC Regional Robotics Award winner - 27th place nationally Visual Basic programming award for academic excellence 2005

SPECIAL ACCOMPLISHMENTS At age 8, built my first computer. At age 10, worked my first job at City Island Computer Services. At age 12, attended my first programming class at Lehman College.